we need to determine what this program
will output
and you can see that we're comparing the
equality of hash one
and hash two if they are equal we'll
output
these hashes are the same otherwise
we're going to output these hashes are
not the same
so taking a closer look at hash one and
hash two
on lines one and two you can see that
although our key value pairs are
in different orders we do have the same
key value pairs in each hash
now they do use a slightly different
syntax in places
to associate a key with a value
for example in hash one we have the key
shoes which is a symbol associated with
the string
nike and this key value pair is written
in this new syntax
in hash two on line 2 we also have
the symbol shoes as a key associated
with the string
nike as the value however this key value
pair uses the older syntax with a hash
rocket
so the question is whether or not these
two hashes are going to
be equal let's run our code
and they are in ruby we aren't relying
on the order of hashes
because we retrieve values based on the
key
now with arrays let's hop into irb
we are relying on the order or index of
each element
so i'm going to create a three element
array
with elements one two and three
and another array with the same elements
in a different order
and when we compare their equality you
can see that it returns false
with arrays order always matters
however as you can see in the program
that we just ran
these two hashes are equal despite the
fact that we've written their key value
pairs in a different order